(南太平洋上的某处 1944年)
《金刚：骷髅岛》
如果我们能利用让我们致胜的
If we can put this tremendous machine of ours,
强大美国军力
which has made this victory possible,
来追求和平
to work for peace,
我们就能展望人类史上最伟大的时代
we can look forward to the greatest age in the history of mankind.
卫星计划的进展速度
Speed of progress in the satellite project
不能作为弹道飞弹成果的
cannot be taken as an index of our progress
进展指标
in ballistic missile work.
(27号指令 布拉沃城堡测试和毁损)
我们的下一个阶段是扩展
I feel we're on the brink of an area of expansion
关于人类本身和周遭环境的知识
of knowledge about ourselves and our surroundings
那在目前仍不可名状或理解
that is beyond description or comprehension at this time.
人类史上第一次 把摄影机放到太空
For the first time, we're putting cameras into space
俯视地球
and looking down on the Earth,
让我们发现前所未见的秘境和奇事
allowing us to discover places and things we've never seen.
未来也界最聪明的居民
The most intelligent inhabitants of that future world
不是人类或猴子
won't be men or monkeys.
而是机器
They'll be machines.
我们在这片未知的海域上启航
We set sail on this new sea
因为有新的知识等着发掘
because there is new knowledge to be gained.
无论这片新海域
Whether this new ocean
会是和平之海
will be a sea of peace
或是可怕的新战场
or a new terrifying theater of war...
"征服人的野性"
"To tame the savageness of man
"使这个也界的生活变得宜人"
"and make gentle the life of this world."
让我们致力于此
Let us dedicate ourselves to that.
停战 停战
Stop the war! Stop the war!
- 停战 - 全市的抗议
- Stop the war! - As citywide protests
使国会委员会的听证会陷入停顿
have brought congressional committee hearings to a standstill,
想见未来几日的交通会更瘫痪
promising more gridlock in the days and weeks ahead.
环线正经历严重堵车
The Beltway is experiencing significant delays.
记住我的话
Mark my words.
华府不会有更糟的时刻了
There'll never be a more screwed up time in Washington.
但我们不能因此却步
But we can't let it stop us.
真是够了 走吧
Come on already, let's go!
别档路
Get out of the way!
也许现在不是开口的好时机
Maybe now's not the best time to ask.
布鲁克斯 帝王计划即将关门大吉 我们破产了
Monarch is on the cusp of being shut down, Brooks. We're broke!
当这场战争结束 我们的考察就永远无法获准
When this war ends, we'll never get approval for our expedition.
我对我们的简报没信心
I'm not confident in our presentation.
我们的所有资料都是散页
All of our materials are loose leaf.
再一天 一天就好
In one day, one day,
我能全部整理装订好
I could have had all of this organized and bound...
今天 我们达成协议
that we, today, have concluded an agreement
结束战争 为越南带来光荣的和平
to end the war, and bring peace with honor in Vietnam.
所有美国军力都会撤退
All American forces will be withdrawn.
我们连一天都没了
We don't have a day.
你好
Hello, there.
比尔·朗达来见威尔斯参议员
Bill Randa here to see Senator Willis.
果然是您 朗达先生
Of course, Mr. Randa.
我今早留了讯息给您 说了今天要改期
I left you a message this morning about rescheduling today's appointment.
但他接下来几周应该有空
But he should have something available in the coming weeks.
见鬼了
Oh, God.
艾尔 你气色真好
Al, you're looking well.
朗达 你没收到我的讯息？
So you didn't get the message, Randa?
- 改期？- 第5次？我一定没注意到
- To reschedule? - For the fifth time? I must've missed it.
我们会速战速决
It'll be quick.
别坐得太舒服 你们只有5分钟
Okay, don't get comfortable. You got five minutes.
我开会要迟到了 那么
I'm late for a meeting. So,
这次你要猎捕什么想像的怪兽？
what imaginary monster are you hunting this time?
这是卫星照片拍到的
This is a satellite photo
南太平洋上一座未知的岛屿
of an uncharted island in the South Pacific.
至今仍是隐密的处女地
It has defied discovery until now.
许多文明的传说中有提到
Many civilizations spoke of it in legends.
骷髅岛
Skull Island.
上帝未造完的国度
The land where God did not finish creation.
它恶名昭彰
It's notorious
许多船和飞机在那里失踪
for the number of ships and planes that have gone missing there.
像是百慕达三角洲？
Like the Bermuda Triangle?
或像我周末喜欢或的防护帽？
Or like that aluminum foil hat that I like to wear on the weekends?
比起帽子倒是更像三角洲
It's more like the triangle than the hat,
但我们认为没那么单纯
but we like to think it's much more than that.
1954年的喝彩城堡核弹测试
The 1954 Castle Bravo nuclear tests
并不是试验
weren't tests.
他们想杀掉某个束西
They were trying to kill something.
我相信那里的生态系统 超乎我们的想像
I believe there's an ecosystem out there the likes of which we can't imagine.
而找到它的地方就是这座岛
And the place to find it is this island.
那里是神秘和科学的交界处
A place where myth and science meet.
朗达 那只是童话
Randa, it's a fairy tale.
杜鲁门在1946年资助帝王计划时 可不这么认为
Harry Truman didn't think so when he funded Monarch in 1946.
就光说浪费吧
In terms of sheer waste,
帝王计划因搜寻外星生物名列前茅
Monarch ranks right up there with the search for alien life.
对 但那些人是疯子
Yeah, but those guys are nuts.
早在几年前就该把你们关闭
We should have shut you down years ago.
这是国家的大好机会
This is an opportunity for our country.
听我说 参议员 大地卫星派人去那座岛出任务
Listen, Senator, Landsat is sending a mission to the island.
我们能顺势搭上他们的行动
We could piggyback on that operation.
当然一定要您的同意
With your permission, of course.
你们希望发现什么？
What're you hoping you'll find?
资源 药材 癌症的解药 地质发现
Resources, medicine, the cure for cancer, geological discoveries. I mean...
可能的替代燃料 参议员
Possible alternate fuels. Senator, look just...
听着 老实说
Listen, to be honest,
我们不确定那里有什么
we don't know for sure what's there.
但我告诉你我们知道什么
Okay? But I will tell you what we do know.
明晚 俄国的诺佛卫星会经过这一区
Tomorrow night, the Russian Novosat passes over this sector.
3天内他们会获得跟我们相同的影像
And in three days, they're gonna have the same images we have.
不管那里有什么
So whatever's there,
您会想要我们先找到
you want us to find it first.
对吧？
Right?
我不敢相信我会这样说 但
I don't believe I'm saying this, but
似乎言之有理
that almost made sense.
谢谢
Thank you.
我会让你们搭上顺风车
So, I will get the piggyback for you. I will.
但听好了 听说我 就这样
But listen to me, listen to me. This is it.
到此为止 就这样
It's gotta end. This is it.
你保证下不为例 好吗？
You promise me? Last favor? Okay?
参议员
Senator?
最后一件事
One last thing.
我需要军方保护
I'm going to need a military escort.
(越南 岘港空军基地)
注意 所有士兵和基地人员
Attention, all soldiers and base personnel.
最后的军队撤退将于6点开始
Final troop withdrawal will commence at 0600.
打包好行李 娘儿们
Pack your bags, ladies.
我们要回家了
We're going home.
- 嘿 米尔斯 - 什么事？
- Hey, Mills. - Yeah?
结果你写给她几封信？
How many letters did you end up writing her?
10到15封吧
Ten, fifteen.
她写给你几封？
How many did she write you?
3或4封吧
I don't know, three, four.
老兄 你老妈真差劲
Man, you got a shitty mom.
科尔 一定要这样说吗 谢谢你
Thank you, Cole, for clearing that up. Thank you.
2天后我见到她时一定会转告
I'll be sure to tell her when I see her in the next 48 hours.
是啊 你可能有个差劲老妈
Yeah, you might have a shitty mom.
对吧？
Right?
美国对共产党明示
The United States is making it clear to the Communists
美国战俘一获释 美军就会撤退
that American troop withdrawal is directly on the release of U.S. prisoners of war.
华府今天已通知
Washington notified the Viet Cong
越共和北越关于彻退…
and North Vietnamese today that the withdrawal...
长官
Sir?
查普曼
Chapman.
长官 需要效劳吗？
You need anything, sir?
我好得很
All good.
了解
Roger that.
查普曼 你回国后打算做什么？
So what're you gonna do when you get back to the world, Chapman?
我已经在东方航空谋得职位
Oh, I'm already set up with Eastern Air Lines.
格雷斯和比利都搬到亚特兰大了
Grace and Billy all moved in in Atlanta,
正在等我回去
just waiting on me.
长官 您呢？
What about you, sir?
这一切是为了什么？
All this for what?
长官？
Sir?
查普曼 走吧 去找点乐子
Get out of here, Chapman. Go have some fun.
没事吧？
ls everything okay?
好极了
Tip-top
派克中校 电话找您
Colonel Packard! There's a phone call for you.
我是派克
This is Packard.
派克 我是沃德将军
Packard, it's General Ward.
你和弟兄们想出最后一趟任务吗？
You and your boys up for one last op?
长官 我倒不反对
I would not be opposed to that, sir.
你们的返家指令已经通过
Your orders to head home are already processed.
确定不想休息一下？
Sure you don't wanna take some time?
我会执行任何下达的指令
I'm here to execute whatever orders I'm given, sir.
别兴奋过头了
Ah, don't get too excited.
一群大地卫星的科学家
Bunch of scientists called Landsat
在卫星上发现一座新岛屿
discovered a new island on their satellite.
他们需要直升机运输 协助调查工作
They need helicopter transport for a survey job.
了解 长官？
Roger that. And, sir?
什么事？
Yes?
谢谢你
Thank you.
朗达 我不懂 你已经争取到军方保护
Randa, I don't get it. You already got us a military escort.
为何需要空降特勤队做向导？
Why do we need a tracker? And why SAS?
前空降特勤队 不效忠任何人
Former SAS. No allegiance to anyone.
1972年他在岘港救了12名坠机飞行员
And he rescued 12 downed pilots in Dé Nang, in '72.
但你的来源说他清醒时
But your source says that he spends most of his waking hours
都在三流酒吧混
in some back alley watering hole.
布鲁克斯 你的耶鲁学历 能带领我们穿越丛林吗？
Is your Yale degree supposed to lead us through the jungle, Brooks?
何况我爸说 别从喝酒的地方评判一个人
Besides, my father told me never to judge a man by where he drinks,
而是从酒品评判
only how he holds it.
你认同我吧？
You on board with me here?
进去
You go.
好吧
Well. Okay.
我们要向他透露多少？
So, uh, how much do we tell him?
只要让他答应就够了
Just enough to get him to say yes.
这样就想走
把钱留下 不然要你好看
你小子给我听好了
这里是我的地盘 你识相点
这家伙值得好好聊聊
Now there's a man worth talking to.
未知的岛屿？
An uncharted island?
让我列出你的各种死法
Let me list all the ways you're gonna die.
暴雨 高温 烂泥 苍蝇和纹子传染的疾病
Rain, heat, mud, disease carrying flies and mosquitos.
当然 你能带着疟疾的治疗药
Sure, you could load up on the atabrine for the malaria,
但其他细菌呢？
but what about the other bacteria?
我们甚至还没聊到想生吞你的玩意
We haven't even started on the things that want to eat you alive.
我们加到两倍
We'll double that.
你们不懂这有多危险
You have no idea how dangerous this is.
我要五倍
I want five times that.
加上如果回得来的分红
Plus, a bonus if we make it back.
如果？
If?
付他
Pay him.
康拉德先生应该获得合理报酬
I think Mr. Conrad should be fairly compensated.
敬和平时期捞一票
Here's to profit during peacetime.
有个问题
One question.
你们来找追踪手
You came here looking for a tracker.
我要追踪谁或什么？
Who or what am I tracking?
我们的资讯仅只于此
This is all the information that we have.
好吗 没有地图
Okay? There is no map.
只有卫星影像
Only satellite images.
所以我们需要你这种高手
So we need someone like you,
凭着你在未知丛林的 独特专业技术
with your skill, your unique expertise in uncharted jungle terrain,
领导我们展开地面探险
to lead us on our ground expedition.
我们只是学者和科学家 我们需要有经验的人
We're just scholars and scientists. We need someone with experience.
以免出了状况
In case things go sideways.
人们参战是为了追寻某种真理 康拉德先生
Men go to war in search of something, Mr. Conrad.
如果你找到了
If you'd found it,
你现在早就回家了
you'd be home by now.
- 韦弗 - 我是杰里
- Weaver. - Yeah, it's Jerry.
嗨 杰里
Hey, Jerry.
告诉我 我中了吗？
So, tell me, did I get it?
大地卫星之旅？你中了
That Landsat thing? You got it.
真的？
I did?
喂？
Hello?
是雅典娜号 停靠在曼谷
It's the Athena, docked in Bangkok.
14号码头 明晚6点
Pier 14, 6:00 tomorrow night.
明晚6点
1800 tomorrow.
谢谢 我欠你个人情
Thank you. I really owe you one.
我不懂 为什么要参加这种测绘地图的活动
I don't get it. Why do you want a gig documenting a mapping mission
你一个能上时代封面的人？
when you're up for the cover of Time?
杰里 既然你三个线人的消息一模一样
Jerry, when three sources tell you the same thing word for word,
你就知道他们在说谎
you know they're lying.
事有蹊跷 某个不能说的秘密
There's something going on here, something that nobody is talking about.
(泰国曼谷)
(14号码头)
我们居然要出任务 没搞错？
I can't believe we're doing this. Are you guys kidding me?
再一天就回家了
A day away.
还有一天就回家了
One day away!
何况还是去另一座岛
And no, now we gotta go to another island
有另一座丛林
with another jungle.
越南不是岛 笨蛋
Vietnam's not an island, dumb-ass.
西礁岛就是
Key West is,
那才是我们该待的地方 手上拿着酒
and that's exactly where I need to be right now, with a drink in my hand.
西礁也不是岛 是礁
Key West ain't an island either, it's a key.
你很无趣 科尔
You ain't funny, Cole.
我是梅森韦弗 摄影师
Mason Weaver, photographer.
梅森·韦弗是女的？
Mason Weaver is a woman?
我没搞错的话
Last time I checked.
需要帮忙吗？
Can I help you?
在境内2年 你属于哪个机构？
Two years in country. Where you been?
安插在美国情报单位
Embedded with MACV-SOG.
你还真有种
Ah, you were in the shit.
向你致敬
I respect that.
但就是你这种人 害我们失去国民支持
But it's people like you lost us support back home.
你不会当真责怪没枪的人…
You're not actually gonna blame the people without guns
打输战争吧？
for losing the war, are you?
相机比枪杆还危险
Camera's way more dangerous than a gun.
而且我们没有打输战争
And we didn't lose the war,
我们是打腻了
we abandoned it.
对
Right.
各位好 欢迎
Hello and welcome.
我是大地卫星的实地监督 维克多·涅韦斯
I'm Landsat Field Supervisor, Victor Nieves.
这是我同事史蒂夫·伍德沃德 我们的资料管理员
This is my colleague Steve Woodward, our data wrangler.
我们探险的目的地
Our expedition takes us to a place
是几世纪以来 人类所知每条航海贸易路径的禁地
every nautical trade route known to man has avoided for centuries.
如我们的卫星显示
As our satellites show,
这座岛受到长期风暴系统包围
the island is surrounded by a perpetual storm system,
让外界一直无法接触
allowing it to remain hidden from the outside world.
但可搭乘派克中校的直升机运输
But with Colonel Packard's helicopter transport,
我们会是深入这处秘境的首例
we will be the first to break through to the other side.
我们也很高兴见到首度加入的
We're also pleased to be joined, for the first time,
资源探勘团队
by the resource exploration team,
向朗达先生领军
led by Mr. Randa
同行的还有生物学家孙小姐
and accompanied by biologist, Miss San,
以及地质学家布鲁克斯先生
and geologist, Mr. Brooks.
我们的重心会是这座岛的表面
Our focus will be on the island's surface,
他们的重心则是地底的物质
theirs, what lies beneath.
布鲁克斯先生
Mr. Brooks.
其实很简单
Simple, really.
我们会用炸弹撼动地表 制造震动
We'll use explosives to shake the earth and create vibrations,
帮助我们勘测岛地表下的
helping us to map the subsurface of the island.
我们在南岸上方 策略性地投下震源药包
We'll fly in over the south shore and then strategically drop seismic charges
进一步了解陆地密度
to better help us understand the density of the earth.
你们要投弹？
You're dropping bombs?
是科学仪器
Scientific instruments.
弟兄们 听到没？
You hear that, boys?
我们变成科学家了
We're scientists now!
你们才不是科学家
You guys are not scientists.
接着我们登陆建立基地营
We'll then land and make base camp
再由康拉德先生带领在地面游走
for ground excursions led by Mr. Conrad.
杰克查普曼少校
Major Jack Chapman.
好 一旦登上那座岛
All right. Once on the island,
风暴的干扰 会切断我们与外界的所有通讯
the storm's interference will block all radio contact with the ship.
那表示我们只能靠自己
That means we'll be by ourselves.
3天后 燃料补给队
Three days later, the refuel team
会在这座岛的北边跟我们会合
will meet us here on the north end of the island.
那是我们唯一安全的离开时机
That may be our only safe departure window for an unknown period of time.
所以给各位建议
So, tip for everybody,
千万别错过了
don't miss it, please.
(禁区 闲人勿进)
(美国陆军 600颗弹药)
(大地卫星)
你在这里干嘛？
What are you doing down here?
我才应该问你
I could ask you the same thing.
为什么地质勘测任务需要炸弹？
Why does a geological mapping mission need explosives?
你没专心听课
You weren't listening in class.
是地质调查用的震源药包
Seismic charges for the geological survey.
是喔 你相信那一套？
Uh-huh. You believe that?
我可没说
I didn't say that.
你见过派克中校了吗？
Have you met Colonel Packard yet?
见过了
Yeah.
那家伙受创很深
The guy's wound pretty tight.
他是战功彪炳的英雄 难免那副模样
Well, the man's a decorated war hero. That's the package they come in.
那你呢？
And you?
对摄影记者来说 绘制地图不会太简单吗？
Isn't shooting a mapping mission a step down for a photojournalist?
适当的照片有能左右舆论
The right photo can help shape opinions.
并能赢得普利兹奖
And win you a Pulitzer.
好 康拉德上尉
Okay, Captain Conrad.
那你呢？
What about you?
英国特种部队怎么会卷入这场行动？
How did British special forces get dragged into this?
叫康拉德就好 我退役了
Just "Conrad." I'm decommissioned.
他们花钱请我
They offered me money.
我看你不像佣兵
You don't strike me as a mercenary.
我看你不像战地摄影师
You don't strike me as a war photographer.
反战摄影师
Anti-war photographer.
查普曼 你在写什么？
What you writing there, Chap?
写信给我儿子
Letter to my boy.
"亲爱的比利"
"Dear Billy,
"我说会在你生日前回家"
"I know I said I'd be home by your birthday,
"但我当着你的面说谎"
"but I lied straight to your face.
"我是个糟糕老爸"
"I'm a terrible dad.
"希望这封信会补偿你"
"I hope this letter makes up for it."
太短了啦
That's too short.
这个风暴亲眼看到更险恶
This storm looks a lot nastier in person.
也许我们该考虑延后任务
Maybe we should consider postponing the mission.
这座岛有多远？
How far away is this island?
80公里 也许更远
50 miles, maybe more.
带我们靠近点
Take us closer.
想起飞就从这里
You wanna launch, you do it from here.
中校 你们能穿越风暴吗？
Can you punch through that, Colonel?
- 我们的机会就是现在 - 穿过这个洞？
- Our opening is now. - Through this hole right here?
对 是难得的低压气穴
Yeah, it's a rare low-pressure pocket.
朗达 我欣赏你的热忱
I appreciate your passion, Randa,
但身为控制机构的实地监督
but as Field Supervisor of the controlling agency,
我建议中止 就这样 我们会中止
I say we abort. That's it, we're gonna abort.
好个明智决定
Wise call.
大地卫星的视察员 一定会被你的勇气激励
I'm sure the Landsat inspector will be inspired by your courage.
不 是被我的常识激励
No, he'll be inspired by my common sense.
这不过是地图探勘
This is only a map survey.
对于地表最后的未知区域之一
To one of the last uncharted areas on the face of the Earth.
你却因下雨放弃？
And you wanna call it on account of rain?
想待在船上随你
Stay on the boat if you want to.
下次我们要等好几年才有这种机会
It could be years before we get another shot at this.
听说你的单位 能够应付这种在暴天气
I'm told your unit is capable of handling inclement weather, Colonel.
就让派克中校打破平局吧
Why don't we leave it to Colonel Packard to break the tie?
我打死不会搭上直升机的
There is no way I'm getting on that helicopter.
我们要求武装直升机 他们不该知道原因吗？
We did ask to arm those helicopters. Shouldn't they know why?
干麻？引起大惊小怪？
Why? And raise an alarm?
不过是以防万一 布鲁克斯
Purely a precaution, Brooks.
是
Right.
再2分钟起飞
Two mikes till launch.
军队和平民登上指定飞机
Troops and civilians, board assigned aircraft.
再2分钟起飞
Two mikes till launch.
那老头让我们淌了什么混水？
What's the old man getting us into, Cole?
他不会害自己送命的 他是带头的
Nothing he wouldn't do himself. He's taking the lead.
他不想念温暖的床吗？我很想念我的床
Doesn't he miss his bed? I miss my bed!
你不想你的床吗？
Don't you miss your bed?
科尔 你有床吗？
Do you even have a bed, Cole?
你有床吧？
You got a bed, right?
查普曼 在会合点见
See you at the rendezvous, Chapman.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
1分30秒 重复 再1分30秒起飞
One mike 30. Repeat, one mike 30 to launch.
完成外物损伤检查 清空甲板
Complete FOD walkdown and clear the deck.
再1分钟起飞
One mike to launch.
- 电池？- 检查了
- Battery? - Check.
- 发电机启动？- 检查了
- Generator start? - Check, check.
- 引擎启动？- 检查三次了
- Engine start? - Check three times.
狐队长呼叫狐小队
This is Fox Leader to Fox Group.
该是时候
It is time, once again,
狮鹫和蚂蚁秀再次登场
for the Griffin and ant show.
老样子 切记
As usual, remember,
坐稳啦
hold onto your butts!
注意 飞行员 准许起飞
Attention, pilots. You are cleared for takeoff.
起飞 起飞 起飞
Launch, launch, launch.
战斗队形
Combat formation.
保持能见度
Keep visual.
狐5号 启航时通知我
Fox Five, let me know when you close.
狐5号就定位
Fox Five is in the slot.
了解
Roger that.
狐小队 列队跟着我 一起行动
Fox team, form up on me. Keep it together!
大家冲了
Let's do this!
维持路线
Maintain course.
我们什么场面没见过
Nothing we haven't done before.
"亲爱的比利"
"Dear Billy.
"你是否曾经凝视飓风并决定…"
"You ever looked into a hurricane and decide,
"也许我该直接冲进去？"
"Maybe I should fly straight through it?
"因为那即将发生了"
"Because that's what's about to happen."
亲爱的比利
Dear Billy.
你最好抓紧
You might wanna hang on.
狐队长呼叫狐小队
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
转为惯性导航
Switch to inertial navigation.
记住伊卡洛斯的故事
And remember the story of Icarus,
他父亲给他蜡造的翅膀
whose father gave him wings made of wax
并警告他别飞得太靠近太阳
and warned him not to fly too close to the sun.
但他太兴奋了
But the exhilaration was too great,
于是他愈飞愈高
so he flew higher and higher
直到太阳熔化了他的翅膀
until the sun melted his wings
他就落入海中
and he fell into the sea.
但美国陆军不是失职的父亲
But the United States Army is not an irresponsible father.
他们给我们的翅膀是热炼冷钆的…
So they gave us wings of white-hot, cold-rolled
宾州钢铁
Pennsylvania steel.
保证不会熔化
Guaranteed not to melt.
喔 嘿 景色很美吧？
Oh, hey, that's pretty, huh?
贴近地表 低空飞行
Let's take them down, low and level.
狐队长呼叫狐小队
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
分头调查各自的区
Split up, survey your zones.
狐7号 让大地卫星人员登陆
Fox Seven, put Landsat on deck.
收到 狐队长 狐3号前往第6区
Copy, Fox Leader. Fox Three headed to Zone Six.
在那里放我们下来
Put us down over there.
其他人跟着队长
Everyone else, stay with the team leader.
把起落架移向3点钟方向
Move that gear to our three o'clock.
快点 动作快
Let's go, let's move it!
准备投震源药包
Ready for seismic charges.
收到
Roger that.
狐小队 可以投了
Fox Group, let it fly.
收到 狐3号 往正东方
Copy all, Fox Three. Heading 0-9-0.
我没看错吧
Are you seeing what I'm seeing?
地震反应太激烈了
The seismic response is incredible.
朗达 你一定不会相信
Hey, Randa, you're not gonna believe this.
岩床…
The bedrock,
实际上是空的
it's practically hollow.
注意前方
Incoming!
小心
Look out!
保持警戎 狐5号
On guard, Fox Five!
狐8号坠落 狐4号坠落
Fox Eight is down! Fox Four is down!
狐3号 请回复
Respond, Fox Three!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
狐7号移往3点钟位置
Fox Seven moving into position, three o'clock.
有谁知道那是什么玩意吗？
Does anybody know what that is?
我不知道 该死
I don't know, man. God damn...
红色降落区以西3公里
Three klicks west of Red LZ.
老天 我从没看过这种怪兽
Jesus! I've never seen anything like it!
设定周边300公尺 不要交战
Set a perimeter of 300 meters. Do not engage.
了解 爬升1800公尺
Roger. Climb 1,800.
那是猴子吗？
Is that a monkey?
那是什么鬼？
What the hell is that?
谁回答我啊
Somebody talk to me, man.
右转 往西南西 目视接近
Turn right, heading 2-5-0. Contact approach...
狐队长呼叫狐小队
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
形成周边 预备炮手位置
Form a perimeter. Ready gunner positions.
我的妈呀 看那玩意 吓死人了
Holy shit! Look at that thing! I'm freaking out here!
狐队长呼叫狐小队 全力开火
Fox Leader to Fox Group. Fire at will!
- 那是什么鬼？- 我不知道
- What the hell is that? - I don't know!
马上撤离 撤离
Pull out now! Pull out!
我可不是听命于你
I don't take orders from you!
快带我们离开
Get us the hell out of here!
- 狐9号坠落 - 哇
- Fox Nine is down! - Whoa!
狐6号 我们快失控了
Fox Six, we got nominal control.
要坠落了
We are going down.
狐5号 这是狐队长 狐9号坠落
Fox Five, this is Fox Leader. Fox Nine is down,
河弯以北1公里
one klick north of river bend.
快派营救队 完毕
Insert recovery team. Over.
狐5号在空中盘旋
Fox Five is hovering.
有人着陆
We got men going out the door!
我需要帮助 我需要…
I need help here. I need...
见鬼
Oh, shit!
干掉这个王八蛋
Kill this son of a bitch.
进攻 我看到了
Coming in hot! I got eyes on it!
拉高
Pull up!
准备冲击
Brace for impact!
求救 求救
Mayday, mayday!
往旁边跑 你白痴喔
Run to the side, you idiot!
- 抓紧了 - 小心
- Hang on! - Watch out!
天啊
Oh, God!
准备坠机
Prepare to crash!
做好准备
Brace!
狐队长坠落
Fox Leader is down!
狐5号回去接应
Fox Five inbound for pickup!
我们看到他了
We have him in sight!
撑住 派克中校 我们正赶过去
Hold tight, Colonel Packard, we are on our way!
撑着 布里吉 我来救你
Hang on, Briggs. I'm coming.
我们要坠落了
We're going down!
重复 我们要坠落了
I repeat, we are going down!
听着 立刻回答我
Listen, I want you to tell me something right now.
- 你爱你老妈吗 - 我爱她
- Do you love your mama? - I love her!
- 你多爱你老妈 - 我超爱我老妈
- How much do you love your mama? - I love my mama so much!
呼叫所有单位 有人在空中吗？
Calling all units! ls anybody airborne?
重复 有人在空中吗？
I repeat, is anybody airborne?
所有人都坠落了 每一架飞机
They're all down. Every one of them.
我们在岛的南边
We're on the south side of the island.
几公里外有一条河
There's a river a couple of klicks from here.
沿着河堤就会到达北岸的撤出点
If we stick to its banks, we'll make it to the exfil site on the north shore.
然后呢？所有直升机都坠落了
And then what? All our choppers are down.
我们想办法向船发信号
We'll find a way to signal the ship.
他们会派出搜救队
They'll send a search party.
我们只要在撤离时间内到达
We just have to make it by the exit window.
我该坐办公桌的
I should be sitting at a desk.
等等 大家都不明讲吗？
So, wait, are we just not gonna talk about this?
我猜我们散落在 6到8公里的半径范围
My best guess is we're scattered over a four to five mile radius.
我们应该往北 沿路找生还者
We should head north and join anyone we find.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我现在回答不出那个问题
I don't know how to answer that question right now.
我也不知道那是什么
I don't know what that was either.
他们是付你多少钱？希望值得
All that money that they paid you? I hope you're worth it.
大家真的都不明讲？
We're really not gonna talk about it?
这不正常吧？这种事平常不会发生
You know this is not normal, right? Stuff like that doesn't just happen!
狐队长呼叫狐小队
This is Fox Leader to Fox Group!
听到的人快回复 完毕
Anybody with ears, come back. Respond. Over.
狐队长 查普曼
Fox, Chapman.
狐6号 查普曼
Fox Six, Chapman.
再说一次你的座标
Say again, your last.
西方4公里 最高峰
Four klicks west, highest peak...
NA300 完毕
November Alpha 300. Over.
了解 查普曼 西方最高山峰
Roger that, Chapman. West highest mountain peak.
完毕
Over.
狐6号确认 我们在海种马直升机旁
Fox Six confirm, we're at the Sea Stallion.
查普曼 留在原地
Chapman, hold your position.
我们去找你 海种马直升机上的弹药
We'll come to you. There's enough munitions
足以杀掉那玩意
on that Sea Stallion to kill this thing.
勘测你的周边
Survey your perimeter.
找出可能的埋伏地点 完毕
Locate possible ambush sites. Over.
查普曼
Chapman.
罗里斯
Reles,
你是在休息 还是可以走了？
taking an R and R day, or you good to go?
长官 我可以走了
I'm good to go, sir.
跟上来
Get him up.
查普曼呼叫所有岗位
Chapman to all stations.
侦察环境
Recon environment.
科尔 你有什么毛病？
Cole, what's wrong with you?
你怎么现在还有胃口？
How you even got an appetite right now?
进食是为了存活
Eating's for the living.
我们刚被一只摩天楼大的猴子痛宰
We just got taken down by a monkey the size of a building!
是啊
Yeah.
那是很不寻常的遭遇
That was an unconventional encounter.
你没吓到头壳坏掉吧？
Is that really all your brain telling itself right now?
没有战术优先次序
There's no tactical precedence.
在这种情况下我们尽力了
We did the best we could in the situation.
狮鹫连
Griffin C0.!
谢天谢地你们没事
Thank God you guys are okay!
- 很高兴见到你 长官 - 我们没事
- Good to see you, sir. - We're all right.
剩下多少人？
How many left?
7人生还
Seven survivors.
7人确认阵亡
Seven confirmed KIA.
贾勒塔 萨拉夫和哈吉斯
Galleta, Saraf, and Hodges.
史利哥和其他人下落不明
Slivko and the rest are unknown.
朗达在哪里？
Where's Randa?
你还好吗？
How you doing?
我很好 谢谢
I'm fine. Thank you.
那好 很高兴听到 我还担心了一下
Good. Glad to hear it. I was worried about you.
你要从实招来所有我不知道的事
You are going to tell me everything I don't know,
否则我会轰了你的脑袋
or I'm gonna blow your head off.
怪兽确实存在
Monsters exist.
废话
No shit.
没人相信我
Nobody believed me.
昨天 我被当成怪胎
Yesterday, I was a crackpot.
但今天…
But today...
所以这从来就跟地质无关
So this was never about geology.
你们投震源药包是要逼出怪物
You dropped those charges to flush something out.
你是什么来头？
Who are you?
你听过美国军舰劳顿号吗？
You heard of the USS Lawton?
民众也没听过
Neither did the public.
那艘船上有一千名年轻人 我是唯一的律存者
Out of a thousand young men on that ship, I was the only survivor.
他们跟我家人说船在战役中沉了
They told my family she was sunk in battle,
但我知道我看到什么
but I know what I saw.
它毫无良心
It had no conscience.
不讲道理 只是破坏
No reasoning, just destroy.
我花了过去30年
I spent the last 30 years
试图证明那天我得知的真相
trying to prove the truth of what I learned that day.
地球不属于我们
This planet doesn't belong to us.
古老物种早在人类之前就拥有地球
Ancient species owned this earth long before mankind.
如果我们继续保持鸵鸟的心态
And if we keep our heads buried in the sand,
它们就会今回地球
they will take it back.
我的机构名为帝王计划
My agency is known as Monarch.
我们专精猎捕巨大不明陆栖生物
We specialize in the hunt for Massive Unidentified Terrestrial Organisms.
你早就知道那个怪物在这里？
You knew that thing was out here?
很遗憾你的属下罹难 我是真心的
I'm sorry for your men, Colonel, I truly am.
送我们回家 带着证据
Get us home, with proof.
我们就能派来装甲部队
So we can send the cavalry.
我就是装甲部队
I am the cavalry.
这称为地空说理论
It's called the Hollow Earth theory.
朗达雇用我…
Randa hired me
因为我写了一篇论文
because I wrote a paper
想证实多数人认为是 异想天开的概念
substantiating what most people think is a crackpot idea.
巨大的地下空间确实存在
That there are these massive underground spaces
- 与表面也界隔离 - 通道
- isolated from the surface world. - Passageways.
朗达相信这座岛可能就是其一
Randa believed this island may be one of those.
地底不明生物的出没点
An emergence point for whatever lives below.
像是刚才看到的古老物种
Ancient species like what we just saw.
我以为他疯了
I thought he was out of his mind.
我是史利哥 有听到吗？
This is Slivko. Do you read?
有人在吗？
Anybody out there?
我们要往北去撤出点
We're headed north to the exfil location.
这里每个人都看起来太冷静了
Everyone here seems way too calm right now.
收到没？有人吗？
Do you copy? Anybody?
超出接收范围 史利哥
We're out of range, Slivko.
该死
Oh, shit.
等留到接近团队时再用
Save it for when we get closer to the group.
谁都不准动
Nobody move.
冷静
Easy.
- 史利哥 - 什么？
- Slivko. - What?
把枪放下
Put it down.
这些人不是白白牺牲
These men did not die in vain.
我对天发誓
I swear to God,
他们不会死不瞑目
their deaths will not go unanswered.
快去找查普曼和那些弹药
Now let's get to Chapman and those munitions.
你听过老鼠 狮子和尖刺的故事？
You ever heard the story of the mouse, the lion, and the thorn?
有
Yeah.
那你就懂了
There you go then.
以免我们又撞见那只猩猩
In case we ever see that primate again.
你的版本是老鼠把狮子脚掌的刺
You do know that story is about a mouse becoming friends with the lion
拔出来后 它们成为好朋友吧？
after taking the thorn out of his paw though, right?
才不是
No, it's not.
老鼠用刺杀死狮子
The mouse kills the lion with the thorn.
谁告诉你的？
Who told you that, Cole?
我妈
My mother.
怪不得你这么天真
That actually explains a lot.
小心 不妙
Look out! Oh, shit!
- 小心 - 那是什么？
- Watch out! - What is it?
- 小心后方 - 上面
- Watch your six! - Up above!
- 在树上 - 朝上开枪
- Up in the trees! - Guns up!
科尔
Cole!
- 不要 - 米尔斯
- No,no! - Mills!
我们会救你
We got you!
我瞄不准
I can't get a shot!
砍断脚 砍断它的脚
Cut the legs! Cut it off at the legs!
我帮你
We got you!
别再想了 快上路
Shake it off, guys! Let's move out.
跟紧
Stay tight.
这是什么鬼？
What the hell is this?
注意后面
Oh! Behind you!
大家保持冷静 保持冷静
Everybody, stay calm. Stay calm.
康拉德
Conrad.
后退
Stay back!
- 大伙儿 - 别靠近
- Guys. - Stop, stop.
- 哇 哇 哇 - 别靠近
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! - Stop, stop!
谁都不准开枪
Nobody shoot!
不要 不必动枪
No, no, no. No need for that.
别激动
Come on now!
各位 镇定下来
Everybody, keep your wigs on now!
怎么回事？
What?
他们说有人来了我还不信
I didn't believe it when they said you were coming.
我整晚没睡
I was up all night
就想着我和军平梦到的这一刻
just thinking about how me and Gunpei dreamed of this moment.
如今实现了
And now here it is.
28年又11个月
28 years, 11 months
8次尝试回归世界都失败
and eight failed attempts to get back to the world,
结果却是你们来找我？
and instead the world comes to me?
不是很爆笑吗？
Ain't that a crack?
他们从不笑的
They never smile.
你在这里坠机？
Did you crash here?
失礼了 小姐
Oh. Sorry, miss.
45步兵团的汉克·马洛中尉
Lieutenant Hank Marlow of the 45th.
为了你穿上旧飞行装
Put the old flight suit on for you.
你美多了…
You are more beautiful
比起热狗配啤酒
than a hot dog and a beer
在里格利球场的开慕日
at Wrigley Field on opening day.
但你是真实的
But you're real.
对吧？
Right?
我就说吧 我不是告诉你们了？
I told you. Didn't I tell you?
我说
I said,
"不要紧的"
"it's fine."
这样才对
There we go.
外头有怪物
There's something out there, man.
外头怪物可多了
Oh, there's a lot out there.
过来 我们快回家
Now, come on. We gotta get home.
晚上最好别在外面
You don't wanna be out here at night.
你们可能注意到 这座岛上有许多怪事
You probably noticed a lot of weird things on this island.
只要待在这群人的部落 我们就会没事
As long as we stay in here where the people live, we'll be all right.
那道墙
That wall,
是为了阻档那只怪兽？
is that supposed to keep out that thing?
不 他们想阻档的不是它
No, he's not the one they're trying to keep out.
什么？
What?
这些人住在树上 不像我们住在地面
These people live up on top of the trees while we're down on the roots.
有些人甚至看不出变老
Some of them don't even seem to age.
没有犯罪
There's no crime,
没有私人财产
no personal property.
他们不在乎那一切
They're past all that.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
好消息
So, good news.
他们说你们能住这里
They say you can shack up here.
我没听到他们说话
I didn't hear them say anything.
他们话不多
Oh, they don't speak too much.
只要你待得跟我一样久 你就会了解 你会明白的
When you've been here as long as I have, you start to understand. You'll see.
等一下 等等
Wait a minute. Wait, wait, wait.
我们不能留下 我们要离开这座岛
We can't stay here. We have to get off the island.
我们还有日子要过
We have lives. I have a life.
尼伟斯 现在时机不对 好吗？
Nieves, now is not the time. All right?
踏上这里 就别想走了
What lands here tends to stay here.
就我所知
As far as I can tell,
这艘船比我早10年冲上岸
this ship washed up about 10 years before I did.
- 你1944年就在这里？- 对
- You've been here since '44? - Yeah.
那场战争的结果呢？我们赢了？
What happened with the war? Did we win?
哪场战争？
Which one?
呃 那说得通
Uh-huh. That makes sense.
这是他们的圣地
This is all hallowed ground to them.
所以不想断手的人 就别乱碰
So if you like your hands, don't touch anything.
真不得了
Look at that.
以他们的说法 几千年来
The way they tell it, for thousands of years,
这座岛上的人活在恐惧中
the people on this island lived in fear.
还真是害怕了很久
That's a hell of a long time to be scared.
然后有一天 最诡异的事发生了
And then, one day, the damnedest thing happened.
他们害怕的一些怪兽
Some of the things they were afraid of
开始保护他们不被其他怪兽吃掉
started protecting them against the things that were eating them.
但凡事都不是永恒的
But nothing lasts forever, I guess.
他们在这里奉杷最后的救世主
And this is where they honor the last of their saviors.
是啊
Yeah.
那是金刚
That's Kong.
他是这里的霸主
He's king around here.
这些人供他为神
He's God to these people.
金刚是个好霸主
Kong's a pretty good king.
习惯独来独往
Keeps to himself mostly.
这是他的家 我们只是客人
This is his home. We're just guests here.
但谁会去别人家里敌丢炸弹
But you don't go into someone's house and start dropping bombs
除非你想够挑起争战
unless you're picking a fight.
不是金刚杀了你朋友？
Wasn't Kong the one who killed your friend?
不是
No.
那种怪兽杀的
One of them did.
金刚是这座岛上的神
Kong's god on the island,
但在我们之下有恶魔
but the devils live below us.
叫什么来着？
And what are they called?
伊维族不会说出它们的名字
The lwis won't speak their name.
但我称它们骷髅爬兽
But I call them Skull-crawlers.
为什么？
Why?
因为听起来特厉害
'Cause it sounds neat.
好吧 我临时编出来
Okay. Look, I just made that name up.
想吓你们的
I'm trying to scare you.
那个名称还不赖
I'm fine calling them that.
- 你说呢？- 同意
- Are you cool with that? - Yeah...
- 我喜欢那个名称 - 感觉是个好名称
- I like the name, so... - That seems like a great name.
我从没说出过那个名称
I've never said that name out loud before.
现在说出来感觉很蠢
it sounds stupid now that I say it.
你们想怎么叫都行
You call them whatever you want.
是一种大蜥蜴 很凶猛
They're big lizard things. Nasty.
来自地底深处的裂缝
They come from the vents deep down.
难怪金刚会抓在
That's why Kong got so mad.
那些炸弹会唤醒其中几只
Those bombs woke up a bunch of them.
说实话 你们很幸运金刚也在
I tell you what. You're lucky he's out there, too,
否则你们活不到现在
or you wouldn't have made it this far.
它们是狡猾的混蛋 残暴至极
They're crafty bastards. Mean as hell.
只要是小只的
Now, he can handle them
金刚就对付得了它们
as long as he gets to them when they're still small.
你不会想要唤醒那只大的
You don't wanna wake up the big one.
- 有多大？- 比较大
- How big is it? - It's bigger.
消灭了它的全家
It wiped out his whole family.
金刚是同类中仅存的 但它仍在成长
Kong's the last of his kind, but he's still growing.
你们最好希望它是
And you better hope he does.
因为伊维族说一旦金刚不在了
Because the lwis say once Kong goes,
那只大恶魔就会出现
then the big one comes up.
那就是大祸临头的时刻了
Then it's, "Goodnight, lrene."
听着 有一支燃料补给队
Listen, there's a refueling team
3天后会抵达这座岛的北边
coming to the north end of the island in three days.
你应该跟我们来
You should come with us.
到岛的北边？
To the north end of the island?
我们要离开这里
We're gonna get out of here.
- 在3天内？- 对
- In three days? - Yes.
不可能在3天内到达北边
You can't get to the north end in three days.
不可能 死心吧 别作梦了
It's impossible. That's it. No way.
至少徒步是不可能的
At least not on foot.
那只鸟丑爆了
That is one ugly ass bird.
亲爱的比利
Dear Billy,
这地方糟透了
this place is hell.
怪兽确实存在
And monsters exist.
在床底下签着薪水条
Under beds and signing paychecks.
- 别闹了 - 这似是
- Come on, man. - Seems like
看来他似乎想去杀那只猩猩
maybe he wants to go kill that ape
而不是让我们离开这座岛 好咧
instead of getting us off this island? Yeah!
我们来不来得及？
Are we even gonna make it?
- 来得及什么？- 到撤出点
- Make what? - The exfil!
我们要在3天内到达
We gotta be there in three days!
我们会赶到 来得及的
We'll make it. We're gonna make it.
但要是查普曼出事…
Yeah, but, Cole, what happens if Chapman's not...
中校说他在那里 他就在那里
The Colonel said he's there, he's there.
我们差一点就… 让这启动
We were this close to getting it working.
我和军平打算动身去外海 设法回家
Me and Gunpei were gonna take off for the open sea, try to get home.
他在那时被怪兽杀了
That's when one of them things got him.
船在那里
There she is.
还真不错
Well, that's lovely.
算你有眼光
You're damn right.
这玩意浮得起来吗？
Does this thing even float?
我和军平花了6年人生建造这艘船
Me and Gunpei spent six years of our lives building this thing.
这是灰狐号
She's called the Grey Fox.
它浮得起来
And she floats.
引擎零件取自我P51战机
Pulled the engine parts from my P-51
和他的零使战机
and his old Zero.
某天在海滩发现一架波音轰炸机 挺管用的
Found a B-29 on the beach one day. That was something.
你别逗了
You gotta be kidding me.
这玩意看起来会让人得破伤风
That thing looks like it's made out of pure tetanus.
这的确看起来不起眼
I know she ain't pretty to look at,
多了人手帮忙 包准能修好
but it's nothing a couple of extra hands can't fix.
除非你们有更好的点子 我建议我们快干活
Unless you got a better idea, I suggest we get cracking.
好吧
All right.
加油 起来
Come on, get up!
看那里
Well, would you look at that?
它流血了
It bleeds.
- 这 - 是我们干的
- Wha... - We did that.
我们要跟查普曼会合
We hook up with Chapman,
那架海种马直升机上有足够的弹药
there's enough munitions on that downed Sea Stallion
能终结它
to finish the job.
太壮观了
Magnificent.
知道为何我带这个却不带M16 ？
You know why I carry this instead of an M-16?
从为越南人民军而战的农夫手上抢来
Took it off a farmer fighting for the NVA.
我们一铲平他的村落他就投降了
He surrendered right after we leveled his village.
他50岁了
He was 50 years old.
说在我们出现前 他根本没看过枪
Said he'd never even seen a gun till we showed up.
有时 敌人并不存在
Sometimes, an enemy doesn't exist
除非你紧追着假想敌
till you go looking for one.
当敌人出现在你门口时又怎样？
What happens when they show up on your doorstep?
我还是会拿着他的枪
I'll still have his gun.
士兵 祝好运
Best of luck with that, soldier.
好 我们有48小时赶到北岸
Okay. So, we've got 48 hours to make it to the north shore.
史利哥 知道你在修什么吧？
Slivko, do you know what you're doing back there?
当然 我爸是技师
Yeah! My pop's a mechanic.
若修不好 他会不认我
If I can't fix this, he'll disown me.
如果他还能再看到我
If he ever sees me again.
暂停一下 英国佬
Hold the phone there, Churchill.
俄罗斯是我们的同盟国
Russia was our ally.
你是说我们正在跟他们作战？
Now, you're saying we're at war with them?
比较像是冷战
It's more of a cold war.
冷战是指…
Cold war like
夏天不开战吗？
they take the summers off?
那小熊队呢 赢了也界大赛吗？
What about the Cubs? The Cubs win a World Series yet?
小熊队？
The Cubs?
拜托 差得可远了
Man, not even close.
他们有强过吗？
Were they ever good?
正好是我的球队 你哪里人？
Happens to be my team. Where are you from?
- 底特律 - 好
- Detroit. - Okay.
好 老虎队 他们今年赢了吗？
Whoa, yeah, the Tigers. Did they win at all this year?
- 我不知道 - 我怀疑
- I don't know. - I doubt it. Yeah.
我永远押小熊赢老虎
I'd pick the Cubbies over the Tigers any day.
你觉得老虎和小熊对打谁会赢？
Who do you think would win in a fight? A tiger or a cub?
老虎会赢
A tiger would win.
对 因为小熊是幼熊
Yeah, because a cub is a baby bear.
成年的老虎能吃掉幼熊
A full-grown tiger can eat a baby bear.
要多动脑筋
Just gotta think it through.
人类也登上月球了
We also put a man on the moon.
真的假的？
No kidding?
他们做了什么 把人丢在那里？
What did they do? Just leave him up there?
他要吃什么？
What's he eating?
国珍 罐头食品
Tang. Spam.
好了 快天黑了
Come on, we're losing daylight.
狐队长 我是查普曼 完毕
Fox Leader, this is Chapman, over.
亲爱的比利
Dear Billy...
有时人生就是会给你致命一击
Sometimes, life just punch you in the balls.
可恶
Damn it.
这是哪门子音乐？
What kind of music is that?
摇摆乐怎么了？
What happened to swing?
班尼·古德曼？
Benny Goodman?
你好像时空旅行者
You're like a time-traveler, man.
听好了 这才是新的声音
I'm telling you, this is the new sound.
(里格利球场 芝加哥小熊队的家)
不知道我剃了须会像谁
I don't know if I'm gonna like whoever's under this beard.
希望你说的那船 能在36小时内带我们到上游
I really hope that thing you call a boat can get us upriver in 36 hours.
如果我们错过时机 我们
Because if we miss that window, we're,
真的就要吃土了
literally, up a creek.
我最初写那篇地空说的论文时
When I first wrote that paper on the Hollow Earth theory,
整个委员会都放声大笑
the whole committee laughed out loud.
除了朗达
Not Randa.
他是唯一把我当一回事的人
The one guy in the crowd who actually took me seriously.
那种感觉很好
It felt good.
但他说地球充满怪兽时 我以为他疯了
Then I thought he was crazy when he said the earth was full of monsters.
我分不清我在说话
I can't tell when I'm talking
- 或没在说话 - 你在说话
- or when I'm not talking. - You're talking.
- 是吗？- 是
- Am I? - Yes.
- 我在说话？- 对
- I'm talking? - Yes.
你的嘴巴在动
Your mouth is moving.
什么？
What?
我会在半夜刺杀你
I'm gonna stab you by the end of the night.
真的？
Really?
开玩笑的
Just kidding.
如果船发动不了 就改搭火车
If the boat doesn't work, we'll just take the train.
最危险的地方始终最美丽 很怪吧？
Isn't it odd the most dangerous places are always the most beautiful?
嗯 我想拍一张长时曝光的照片
I'm trying to take a long-exposure photograph,
但我的闪光灯坏了
but my flashlight broke.
试试这个
Try this.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 皇家空军？- 是我爸的
- Royal Air Force? - It was my father's.
他出发去打纳粹时从火车上扔给我
He threw it to me from the train as he rolled off to fight the Nazis.
他就像是我的约翰·韦恩
He was like John Wayne to me.
某种神话的英雄
Some kind of mythic hero.
他有回来吗？
Did he come back?
他的飞机坠落在汉堡附近
His plane went down near Hamburg.
他们搜寻他几个月但…
They searched for him for months but...
我想没人会从战场回家
I suppose no man comes home from war.
心是回不来了
Not really.
米尔斯 别打混了 我要去检查周边
Mills, quit dicking around. I'm going on perimeter.
派克中校
Colonel Packard,
前往坠机地点的任务并不明智
this mission to the crash site is folly.
我能理解你寻人心切
I understand going after your man.
但除此之外
But the rest of it...
这不是我们能力所及
This is beyond us.
你不喜欢我的处事方式？
You don't like the way I'm running things?
想走人随你
You know where the door is.
你促成这次行动 硬闯这片禁地
You set this in motion when you put this place on the map.
但我绝不会临阵脱逃
And I will not cut and run.
我看到敌人绝不放过
I know an enemy when I see it.
这个人的名字是和军平
This man's name was Gunpei lkari.
但只要脱去制服
But you take away the uniforms
还有战争
and the war...
他成为我的兄弟
He became my brother.
我们发誓绝对不会丢下对方
And we swore we'd never leave each other behind.
咱们离开这座岛吧
Let's get off this island.
还没啦
Not yet!
- 把油加满 - 好
- Prime the lines. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
搞定了 出发
Wind it up, let's go!
继续转
Keep going!
第三次就会成功 加油 加油
Third time's the charm. Here we go. Here we go!
加把劲 加把劲
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
加油 加油
Come on, come on.
好耶
Yes.
好耶 发动了
Yes! Yes!
该是道别的时候了
I guess this is goodbye.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你们有来芝加哥 记得找我
If you're ever in Chicago, look me up, I guess.
拿来 让我帮忙
Here, no. Let me help.
男人就该… 啊
Man's gotta do what... Ow!
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我没事
I'm okay.
让我来吧
Allow me.
你该在图书馆认识我
You should see me in the library.
我有老婆
I got a wife.
曾经有老婆
Had a wife.
老婆还在吗？
Have a wife?
我已经不得而知了
Guess I don't know anymore.
我们在我参战前结婚
We got hitched right before I deployed.
我坠机的前一天收到电报
Got a telegram from her the day before I got shot down.
她说我们的儿子刚出生
She said we just had our baby boy.
我有个儿子
I got a son out there.
我从没见过的成年人
Grown man I've never met.
她肯定以为你挂点了
Yeah, she definitely thinks you're dead, man.
嘿
Hey!
我只是说说
I'm just saying.
很难说
You don't know that.
有些人就是很能等
You'd be surprised how long people wait.
事实上 我不指望他们等待
Ah, truth is, I don't expect them to be waiting.
反正我会没事的
I'd be fine either way.
我只想有机会见到他们一面
I just want one last chance to see them.
那样我就满足了
That'd be good enough for me.
我们会送你回家的
We're gonna get you home.
狐5号 回复
Fox Five, come back.
那里有人吗？
Is there anyone out there?
这是狐5号 我们听到了
Hey! This is Fox Five. We hear you.
对 我们在船上
Yeah! We're on a boat.
- 我们在船上 在河上往北 - 船？
- We're on a boat headed up north on a river. - A boat'?
哪弄来的？
Where'd y'all get a boat?
我们遇到一个疯颠的圣诞老人
We met this, like, crazy Santa Claus,
来自二战的时空旅行者 你们会见到他
time-traveler guy from World War ll. You'll meet him.
你们弄来什么船？
What kind of boat y'all got?
其实比较像飞机
It's more of, like, a plane than a boat, really.
就称"飞机船"好了
Let's call it a "ploat."
我们在飞机船上
We're on a ploat.
史利哥 我们需要他们的位置
We need their location, Slivko.
发射信号弹 让我们找到你们
Send up a flare so we can find you.
了解 狐5号
Roger that, Fox Five.
要发射了
Fire in the hole!
那里
There!
好
Yes!
重复 看到了 在我们北方2公里
I repeat, we have a visual. Two klicks to our north.
了解 狐5号 狐1号结束
Roger that, Fox Five. Fox One out.
1 小时后在集合点会合
Rendezvous point, one hour.
上路了
Mount up!
船装得下所有人吗？
Can we fit everybody?
好耶
Yes!
我们要回家了
We 're going home!
给我下来
Get down!
搞什么鬼？
What the hell, man?
他死了
He's gone.
拿好各自的装备 我们要继续移动
Everybody, grab your gear. We have to keep moving.
我们上岸跟派克会合
We'll go ashore, meet up with Packard.
不 等一下
No. Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
没人要说点什么 刚才…
Is nobody gonna say anything about the...
他挂了
He's gone!
回不来了 没啥好说的
And he ain't coming back. There's nothing to say.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
信号弹在北方2公里
Their flare was only two klicks north.
他们应该很快会到
They should be here soon.
除非被比我们大的怪物吃了
Unless they were eaten by something that's bigger than us.
老天爷
Holy shit!
史利哥
Slivko!
我以为你喝屁了
Thought you were taking a dirt nap by now, Slivko.
没想到能再见到你们
Never thought I'd see you guys again.
- 我以为你疯了 - 你看到的人
- I thought you were crazy. - I wish I had been.
- 你还剩多少人？- 你看到就是全部的人了
- What's your count? - What you see is what I got.
我们也失去一个人
We lost one, too.
很高兴见到你们
Good to see you, fellas!
这是何方神圣？
Who the hell is this?
我们让他搭便车
We picked up a hitchhiker.
汉克·马洛上尉 第15航空队第45中队
Lieutenant Hank Marlow of the 45th Pursuit Squadron of the 15th.
你从二战就在这里？
You've been here since World War II?
没错 我错过阅兵了？
Yes, sir. I miss the parade?
真要命
I'll be damned.
敬礼 中尉
Snap to, Lieutenant.
我们会送他回家
We're gonna get him home, sir.
只要沿着这条河
If we follow this river,
赶上了船 就能及时到达北岸
we'll make it to the boat, and we'll make it to the north shore in time.
好主意
That sounds good.
但我们还不能离开
But we're not leaving yet.
还有一人失踪 康拉德
Still got a man out there, Conrad.
等一下 还有一人个？
Wait a second. You got someone out there?
查普曼
Chapman.
他在坠落的海种马旁 在西边
He's with the downed Sea Stallion just west of here.
西边？我们不能往西
West? We can't go west!
那些骷髅爬兽就住那里
That's where the skull things live.
当地有句古谚:"东方棒棒哒 西方糟透了"
We have an old saying here. "East is best, west is worst!"
这样说是有道理的
That's why we say it!
至于西南…
You know, southwest...
还可以商量
We could talk about that.
但要往西的话需要更多枪
But you're gonna need a lot more guns if you're gonna go west.
各位 我们应该听马洛的
Guys. I think that we should listen to Marlow.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
嘿
Hey...
你的工作是找到失踪的人 对吧？
Your job is finding lost men, right?
你说了算
Okay, sir.
但如果我们到达那里他却不在
But if we reach that position and he's not there,
我们不会派人搜索
we don't send out a search party.
要在傍晚前会回来这里 懂吗？
We're back here by nightfall, understood?
在24小时内得赶到岛的另一边
In 24 hours, we have to be on the other side of this island.
了解 听得一清二楚
Roger that. Hear you loud and clear.
你们听到了 10分钟后出发
All right, you heard the man. Moving out in 10.
真是一群好兄弟
This is a good group of boys.
我们都会一起死在这里
We're all gonna die together out here.
我承认跟你们这群兄弟 一起死还不赖
You're a good group of boys to die with, I'll tell you that much.
你们不该来这里的
You shouldn't have come here.
记得提醒我 这是个馊主意
Don't forget to tell me this is a bad idea.
这是个馊主意
This is a bad idea.
嘿 你们闻到了吗？
Yeah, you smell that?
那是死亡的味道
That's death.
这到底是什么地方？
What the hell is this place?
这是金刚父母的遗骸
This is what's left of Kong's parents.
我拍了够多敌葬岗 算是认得出来
I've taken enough photos of mass graves to recognize one.
坠机地点在这座山谷的另一边
The crash site's just on the other side of this valley.
我们会穿过 爬上西方的最高点
We'll cross through and make it to the highest point west.
这地方是禁地
This place is a real no-no, sir.
我们需要立刻去北边
We need to be going to the north side right now.
你请便 老兄
And you're welcome to do that, my man.
自己去
By yourself.
我不会丢下杰克 谁会跟我去？
I'm not leaving Jack out there. Now, who's with me?
我们会成功的
We can make it.
对极了 我们会成功的
You're mighty right, we can make it.
机灵点 睁大眼睛
Now, stay sharp. Keep an eye out.
我在这里只待28年 老子懂什么
I've only been here 28 years. What do I know?
科尔 没时间了 把烟熄掉
Cole, we don't got time for that, man. Put the cigarette out.
小心那些烟
Watch those fumes!
白痴
Idiots.
走吧 我们要赶快
Let's go. We gotta move!
快逃
Run!
躲在这里
In here!
安静
Quiet.
我就说这鬼地方是禁忌
I told you this damn place was a no-no.
该死
Damn it.
好 快走
All right, let's move.
队伍跟着我
Rally on me.
整队 整队
Rally up! Rally up!
谁去保护那些平民 赶快
Somebody cover the civilians' six. Let's move!
见鬼
Oh, shit.
朗达
Randal
预备机关枪
Set up the 50!
宁死不屈
快走
Go!
拿喷火器 喷个痛快
Bring the torch! Do your thing!
史利哥
Slivko!
有毒气
Gas!
马洛 剑给我
Marlow! Sword!
史利哥 等我
Slivko, hang on!
怪兽在移动
This thing's moving!
听着 中校
Now, look, Colonel.
你可能阶级比我高
You may outrank me,
但我待在这里可久了
but I've been here a hell of a lot longer.
我郑重告诉你
And I'm telling you
刚才打爆我们的玩意 只是刚开始的一只
that thing that just shredded us was only the first of them.
我们闯入它们的地盘
Now we're on their turf,
我们需要立马回头
and we need to turn back toot sweet!
只要查普曼还在那里就不行
Not as long as Chapman's still out there.
很遗憾 派克中校
I'm sorry, Colonel Packard.
查普曼死了
Chapman is dead.
计划不变
Doesn't change a thing!
我们仍会去坠机地点
We're still going to that crash site.
你到底想在那里找到什么？
What's at that crash site that you want so badly?
武器 足以干掉它的武器
Weapons! Enough to kill it.
- 金刚没杀查普曼 - 但他杀了这些人
- Kong didn't kill Chapman. - But he did kill these men!
我的弟兄们
My men!
中校 你不能杀金刚
You can't kill Kong, Colonel.
金刚是这座岛上的神
Kong is god on this island.
只有它能阻档大蜥蜴爬出地表
He's the only thing keeping them lizard things in the ground.
中校 他说的对 我们不能杀金刚
He's right, Colonel. We can't kill Kong.
至于另一种怪物？
Now, that other creature?
那才是威胁 下面有更多只
That's the threat. And there are more of them down there.
如果你破坏物种的自然竞争
If you take away a species' natural competition,
它们会繁殖到失控
they'll proliferate out of control.
那我们也要终结它们
Then we'll end them, too!
在我们拿下金刚之后
After we bring this thing down.
中校 我不能让你那样做
I can't let you do that, Colonel.
等等 停火
Whoa, whoa. Wait! Hold your fire!
我们绝对不会输掉这场战争
This is one war we are not gonna lose.
疯子
Nuts!
你听到了 这简直疯了
You hear me? This is nuts!
拜托 你要听我们的
Please! You need to listen to us!
这不是交战 你会铸成大错
We're not at war, Colonel. You're making a mistake.
你们的谎言害我的属下被杀
Your lies got my men killed!
- 你会害所有人被杀 - 这不是我们的战争
- And you're gonna get us all killed! - Not our fight.
上尉 你站哪一边？
Whose side are you on, Captain?
好吧 中校
Okay, Colonel.
你去那座山脊找你的海种马
You'll find your Sea Stallion three klicks up that ridge.
我会带这些平民回到船上
Now, I'm gonna take these civilians back to the boat.
我们会在那里等你们
And we'll wait for you there.
好吗？
All right?
准备出发
Saddle up!
去杀掉金刚吧
Let's go kill this thing!
史提夫
Steve,
你要跟我们去打怪 或跟他们去纳凉？
you running with the big dogs or staying on the porch?
我不想去纳凉
I don't wanna be on the porch.
马洛 你没事吧？
Marlow, you okay?
我们得阻止他
We need to stop him.
你还想跟他争辩？
You wanna talk with him about it again?
他一开始就很坚决
He seemed to really go for it the first time.
他失去理智了
He's losing his grip.
跟着我
Now, follow me,
我们会活着离开这座岛
and we'll get off this rock alive.
亲爱的比利
Dear Billy...
我正设法回家找你和你妈
I'm just trying to get home to you and your mom.
你要坚强喔
You be strong, now.
满满的爱
Much love.
确定他的家人会收到
Make sure those get back to his family.
亲爱的比利
Dear Billy...
你爸是最优秀的军人
Your dad was one of the best to ever do it.
附近有水源
There's water close by.
你迷路了吗 走哪一边？
Are you lost? Which way?
等等
Hang on.
在这里等
Wait here.
我要到高处找到河
I've got to get to higher ground to find the river.
我也去
Hey! I'm coming, too.
我在这里守着
I'll be right here.
保持警戎
Keep your eyes open.
也要小心树上
Up in the trees, too.
为什么？
Why?
蚂蚁
Ants.
很大只的
Big ones.
那里就有一只
There's one.
听起来像鸟 但居然是蚂蚁
Sounds like a bird, but it's a fucking ant.
尽量收集弹药 包括震源药包
Gather up everything you can, including those seismic charges.
第一次投弹就引起了它的注意
They got his attention the first time.
这是个馊主意
This is a bad idea.
见机行事吧
Let's just get on with it.
米尔斯 科尔
Mills, Cole,
准备好炸弹
let's prep this ordinance.
特别招待它汽油弹
Make him a special gift out of that napalm.
船一定在河弯附近
The boat must be around that bend.
我们该走了 赶快
We have to go. Now.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
康拉德 我们要走哪边？
Conrad, which way are we going?
你们三人回去船上 往那边
You three need to go back to the boat. It's that way.
等我们到黎明
Wait for us till dawn.
如果到时我们还没回来
If we're not back by then,
就先走吧
Just go.
不必你逼我也会走
You ain't gotta twist my arm.
你们俩要去哪里？
Where are you two going?
我们要去救金刚
We're going to save Kong.
伙伴 少不了我
Not without me, pal.
老天
Oh, dear.
兄弟们
Men!
预备冲锋
Place your charges.
该是时候向金刚证明…
It's time to show Kong
人类才是王者
that man is king!
1号炸弹
Arm one.
2号炸弹
Arm two.
3号炸弹
Arm three.
派克
Packard!
千万不要
Don't do it.
我这次不会跟你们好好说
I asked you fellas nice the first time.
我们别在这里争吵
We don't wanna fight here, Packard.
它害我们坠机 杀了我的属下
This thing brought us down! It killed my men!
金刚只是在扞卫自己的地盘
Kong was just defending his territory.
我们是军人
We are soldiers!
我们负责干肮脏勾当
We do the dirty work,
好让我们的家人和同胞不必害怕
so our families and our countrymen don't have to be afraid!
他们甚至不该知道这玩意的存在
They shouldn't even know a thing like this exists!
你疯了
You've lost your mind.
放下引爆器
Put that detonator down.
住手
Stop!
别把世界想得这么狭隘
The world is bigger than this.
女人 少插手
Bitch, please!
史利哥 把她带走
Slivko, get her out of there!
孩子 你明知这样做是错的
You know it's the wrong thing to do, son.
把它放下 长官
Put it down, sir.
派克
Packard!
认清吧
Come on.
结束了
It's over.
那就是大的
That's the big one.
撤退
Fall back.
快走
Go!
中校
Colonel.
长官
Sir!
去死吧 你这王八…
Die, you mother...
金刚倒下了 快走
Kong's down. Let's go!
他们要我们黎明时离开
They told us to leave at dawn.
- 我知道 - 已经黎明了
- I know. - It's dawn.
我知道啦
I know!
我们怎么办？
So what are we going to do?
这是岛的边缘
This is the edge of the island.
韦弗 爬上岩壁发射信号弹
Weaver, get up on those rocks and fire a flare.
运气好的话 布鲁克斯会看见
With any luck, Brooks will see it.
我们会帮你争取时间
We'll buy you time.
这边
This way.
快点 分秒不能浪费
Come on. Every second counts.
科尔
Cole!
过来 我们要撤退
Come on, man, we gotta fall back.
享受你们的人生
Go live your life.
离开这里
Get out of here.
- 科尔 不要 - 科尔
- Cole, no! - Cole!
- 科尔 不要 - 别去
- Cole, no! - Stop!
- 科尔 - 科尔 科尔
- Cole! - Cole! Cole!
不要 别去
No! Don't!
科尔
ALL: Cole!
Cole!
放马过来 你这王八蛋
Come on. Come on, you son of a bitch.
快点 快走
Come on! Go!
快点 赶快
Come on! Hurry!
快点
Come On!
马洛 帮个忙
Marlow, a little help here!
我来 这玩意会闹脾气 当心
I got it. She's temperamental. Watch out!
- 搞定 - 搞定
- Clear! - Clear!
来啊 你这混蛋
Come on, you bastard!
韦弗
Weaver!
韦弗 韦弗
Weaver? Weaver.
醒醒
Hey, hey, hey... Hey...
你没事了
You're okay.
伙伴们 你们觉得呢？
So what do you think, fellas?
一路开去西礁岛
This way to Key West?
应该是 兄弟
I think it is, brother.
这个地方会改观
This place will change.
消息会传开来
Word will get out.
迟早的事
It always does.
至少不会从我们口中说出
Well, it's not coming from us.
我们会重逢
We'll meet again
不知在哪里
Don't know where
不知在何时
Don't know when
但我知道我们会重逢
But I know we'll meet again
各位
Ladies and gentlemen,
进入第8局小熊队进攻
here we go now to the Cub half of number eight.
如果你想看疯在群众
If you want to see a crowd go crazy,
就看这位选手有没有击出
see what happens if this guy hits one right now.
球飞得很远
Fly ball, very deep.
不可能的梦想
And the impossible dream
刚才美梦成真了
just became the possible dream!
你们打算坐在那里？
You just gonna sit there?
在黑暗中
In the dark.
你们乐在其中 对吧？
You're enjoying this, right?
你们把这当成乐趣？
Is this fun for you?
我保证不会告诉俄国人
I promise I won't tell the Russians.
- 我保证会告诉俄国人 - 她会告诉俄国人
- I promise I will tell the Russians. - She's gonna tell the Russians.
为什么把我们关在这里？
Why are you keeping us here?
- 我想要回家 - 我们懂了
- I wanna go home. - We get it.
根本没有岛
There was no island.
我们从没去过岛上
We were never on an island.
岛？
Island?
什么岛？
What island?
布鲁克斯 搞什么？
Brooks, what the hell is going on?
欢迎来到帝王计划
Welcome to Monarch.
这座岛只是开端
This island is just the beginning.
那里有更多秘密
There's more out there.
"更多"是什么意思？
What do you mean, "more"?
这也界从不属于我们 是属于它们
This world never belonged to us. It belonged to them.
问题是 还要多久它们会今回来
The question is how long before they take it back.
金刚不是唯一的霸主
Kong is not the only king.
(最高机密 帝王计划)
(第8区 更多威胁)